Alp Oran

■ alporan@outlook.com □ +90 (537) 513-4529 ■ www.linkedin.com/in/alp-oran • https://www.github.com/alporan

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of developing, testing, and maintaining software systems. Strong problem-solving skills with an analytical mindset. Quick adaptation to new technologies, challenges, and responsibilities. Experience working as part of a productive team, as well as effectively self-managing during personal projects.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Development Engineer

Amadeus · Istanbul - Turkey

Mar 2022 - Present

- · Developing contract and airport billing system as a part of the Airport Management Suite.
- · Maintenance of legacy Swing application.
- · Conducting code reviews and knowledge transfer meetings.

Tools: Angular, Java 17, Spring Framework, Hazelcast, Hibernate, Drools, Maven, Jenkins, JBoss, Azure Logic Apps, Atlassian Stack, Scrum Framework.

Software Engineer

Şekerbank T.A.Ş. · Istanbul, Turkey

Oct 2020 - Mar 2022

- · Developed applications for the middleware utilized by digital banking channels (Web/Mobile Branches, Call Centers, IVR, etc.).
- · Engineered a back-end for the front-end layer for the digital channels UI modernization project.
- · Maintenance of legacy JSP/Servlet-based J2EE web application.

Tools: Java 8, Spring Framework, Hibernate, Open API, Maven, IBM WebSphere, Atlassian Stack, Scrum Framework.

Software Engineer

BilgeAdam Technologies · Istanbul - Turkey

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

· Worked as a consultant software engineer at Şekerbank T.A.Ş.

Software Engineer

Turkish Airlines · Istanbul - Turkey

Sep 2017 - Sep 2020

- \cdot Developed and maintained mainframe applications for reservation, ticketing, and DCS systems.
- · Migrated mainframe applications to open systems as part of architectural transformation projects.
- · Automated manual tasks and test cases for dummy terminals with Python Programming Language

Tools: IBM High-Level Assembler, Java, Spring Framework, Agile Practices.

EDUCATION

Information Technologies

Sakarya University · Master of Science · Istanbul, Turkey

2018 - 2020

Electronics and Communications Engineering

Istanbul Technical University ⋅ Bachelor of Science ⋅ Istanbul, Turkey

2011 - 2015

CERTIFICATIONS

IELTS (International English Language Testing System) · IDP Education

Reading: 9/9, Listening: 8.5/9, Speaking: 7/9, Writing: 6/9

2015

TOEFL (Test of English as a Foreign Language) · Educational Testing Service (ETS)

Reading: 26/30, Listening: 26/30, Speaking: 19/30, Writing: 21/30

2015

SKILLS